A Guide to the Board minutes and record books of the Virginia Dept. of Alcoholic Beverage Control, 1934-1998
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Board minutes and record books of the Virginia Dept. of Alcoholic Beverage Control, 1934-1998
The Library of Virginia
44438
39.25 cu. ft. (157 volumes)
Virginia Dept. of Alcoholic Beverage Control
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred 13 August 2009 from the Virginia Dept. of Alcoholic Beverage Control Board, 2901 Hermitage Rd., Richmond, Virginia 23230.
Biographical Information
The Alcoholic Beverage Control Board and its administrative arm, the Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control, were created by an act of the General Assembly passed on March 7, 1934. The act, known as the Alcoholic Beverage Control Act, which the department was established to administer, specified the circumstances under which alcoholic beverages could be purchased and consumed. The act has been amended over the years. A major change occurred on February 7, 1968, when the General Assembly approved the sale of mixed drinks on a local option basis. The Board has three members appointed by the governor and confirmed by the General Assembly. It establishes rules and policies governing the Department, which controls through licenses and permits, the manufacture, bottling, selling, advertising, and transporting of alcoholic beverages; operates state stores for the sale of beverages, other than beer, to consumers and licensees. The Commissioner operates out of the Richmond office, with district offices established in Abingdon, Alexandria, Charlottesville, Chesapeake, Hampton, Lynchburg, Roanoke, and Staunton.
Scope and Content
Contains minute books of the Board of Alcoholic Beverage Control from 1934 until 1998. Also contains record books containing orders, including administrative and regulatory orders, from 1934 until 1985.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into two series:
Series I: Minute books, 1934-1998
Series II: Record books, 1934-1985
Contents List
- Series I: Minute books, 1934-1998, Extent: 36 cu. ft. (144 volumes) (Box Volumes 1-144)
  - Minute books, 1934 Mar 22-1934 Aug 31 (Volume 1)
  - Minute books, 1934 Sept 6-1934 Dec 31 (Volume 2)
  - Minute books, 1935 Jan3-1935 June 29 (Volume 3)
  - Minute books, 1935 July 9-1935 Dec 30 (Volume 4)
  - Minute books, 1936 Jan 2-1936 June 30 (Volume 5)
  - Minute books, 1936 July 2-1936 Nov 30 (Volume 6)
  - Minute books, 1936 Dec 1-1937 Apr 30 (Volume 7)
  - Minute books, 1937 May 4-1937 Aug 30 (Volume 8)
  - Minute books, 1937 Sept 1-1937 Dec 30 (Volume 9)
  - Minute books, 1938 Jan 3-1938 June 30 (Volume 10)
  - Minute books, 1938 July 1-1938 Oct 31 (Volume 11)
  - Minute books, 1938 Nov 3-1939 Mar 30 (Volume 12)
  - Minute books, 1939 Apr 3-1949 June 30 (Volume 13)
  - Minute books, 1939 July 1-1939 Sept 29 (Volume 14)
  - Minute books, 1939 Oct 3-1940 Mar 26 (Volume 15)
  - Minute books, 1940 Apr 2-1940 June 28 (Volume 16)
  - Minute books, 1940 July 1-1940 Dec 27 (Volume 17)
  - Minute books, 1941 Jan 1-1941 June 26 (Volume 18)
  - Minute books, 1941 July-1941 Oct 30 (Volume 19)
  - Minute books, 1941 Nov 5-1942 Apr 30 (Volume 20)
  - Minute books, 1942 May 1-1942 June 29 (Volume 21)
  - Minute books, 1942 Oct 1-1943 Mar 31 (Volume 22)
  - Minute books, 1943 Apr 1-1943 Sept 30 (Volume 23)
  - Minute books, 1943 Oct 1-1944 Apr 28 (Volume 24)
  - Minute books, 1944 May 1-1944 Oct 31 (Volume 25)
  - Minute books, 1944 Nov 1-1945 Apr 30 (Volume 26)
  - Minute books, 1945 May 1-1945 Oct 31 (Volume 27)
  - Minute books, 1945 Nov 1-1946 Apr 30 (Volume 28)
  - Minute books, 1946 May 1-1946 Oct 31 (Volume 29)
  - Minute books, 1946 Nov 6-1947 May 29 (Volume 30)
  - Minute books, 1947 June 2-1947 Dec 31 (Volume 31)
  - Minute books, 1948 Jan 6-1948 July 30 (Volume 32)
  - Minute books, 1948 Aug 2-1948 Dec 30 (Volume 33)
  - Minute books, 1949 Jan 4-1949 July 28 (Volume 34)
  - Minute books, 1949 Aug 1-1950 Jan 31 (Volume 35)
  - Minute books, 1950 Feb 2-1950 July 31 (Volume 36)
  - Minute books, 1950 Aug 1-1951 Jan 30 (Volume 37)
  - Minute books, 1951 Feb 1-1951 July 31 (Volume 38)
  - Minute books, 1951 Aug 2-1952 Mar 31 (Volume 39)
  - Minute books, 1952 Apr 1-1952 Dec 31 (Volume 40)
  - Minute books, 1953 Jan 2-1953 Sept 30 (Volume 41)
  - Minute books, 1953 Oct 1-1954 June 30 (Volume 42)
  - Minute books, 1954 July 1-1955 Jan 27 (Volume 43)
  - Minute books, 1955 Feb 2-1955 Sept 26 (Volume 44)
  - Minute books, 1955 Oct 3-1956 June 26 (Volume 45)
  - Minute books, 1956 July 2-1957 Mar 29 (Volume 46)
  - Minute books, 1957 Apr 3-1957 Dec 31 (Volume 47)
  - Minute books, 1958 Jan 2-1958 Sept 30 (Volume 48)
  - Minute books, 1958 Oct 2-1959 Aug 5 (Volume 49)
  - Minute books, 1959 Aug 5-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 50)
  - Minute books, 1960 May 10-1960 Dec 29 (Volume 51)
  - Minute books, 1961 Jan 3-1961 June 29 (Volume 52)
  - Minute books, 1961 Oct 3-1962 June 29 (Volume 53)
  - Minute books, 1962 July 3-1963 Mar 29 (Volume 54)
  - Minute books, 1963 Apr 4-1963 Dec 30 (Volume 55)
  - Minute books, 1964 Jan 2-1964 Sept 30 (Volume 56)
  - Minute books, 1964 Oct 2-1965 Sept 30 (Volume 57)
  - Minute books, 1965 Oct 5-1966 Aug 30 (Volume 58)
  - Minute books, 1966 Sept 6-1967 Aug 31 (Volume 59)
  - Minute books, 1967 Sept 1-1968 Sept 30 (Volume 60)
  - Minute books, 1968 Oct 1-1969 Sept 30 (Volume 61)
  - Minute books, 1969 Oct 1-1970 Oct 30 (Volume 62)
  - Minute books, 1970 Nov 2-1971 June 30 (Volume 63)
  - Minute books, 1971 July 1-1972 June 6 (Volume 64)
  - Minute books, 1972 June 9-1973 Mar 30 (Volume 65)
  - Minute books, 1973 Apr 3-1974 Mar 29 (Volume 66)
  - Minute books, 1974 Apr 2-1975 Jan 27 (Volume 67)
  - Minute books, 1975 Feb 3-1974 Dec 23 (Volume 68)
  - Minute books, 1976 Jan 2-1976 Dec 19 (Volume 69)
  - Minute books, 1977 Jan 3-1977 Dec 21 (Volume 70)
  - Minute books, 1978 Jan 5-1978 Sept 27 (Volume 71)
  - Minute books, 1978 Oct 2-1979 Sept 26 (Volume 72)
  - Minute books, 1979 Oct 19-1980 June 30 (Volume 73)
  - Minute books, 1980 July 1-1981 Mar 31 (Volume 74)
  - Minute books, 1981 Apr 6-1981 Dec 31 (Volume 75)
  - Minute books, 1982 Jan 4-1982 Dec 29 (Volume 76)
  - Minute books, 1983 Jan 3-1983 Dec 29 (Volume 77)
  - Minute books, 1984 Jan 4-1984 Dec 2 (Volume 78)
  - Minute books, 1985 Jan 2-1985 Dec 30 (Volume 7)
  - Minute books, 1986 Jan 2-1986 Dec 23 (Volume 80)
  - Minute books, 1987 Jan 9-1987 Dec 28 (Volume 81)
  - Minute books, 1988 Jan 4-1989 June 30 (Volume 82)
  - Minute books, 1989 July 5-1990 Mar 31 (Volume 83)
  - Minute books, 1990 Apr 2-1992 Apr 30 (Volume 84)
  - Minute books, 1991 Apr 1-1992 Apr 30 (Volume 85)
  - Minute books, 1992 May 1-1993 June 24 (Volume 86)
  - Minute books, 1993 July 2-1994 Mar 31 (Volume 87)
  - Minute books, 1993 July 2-1993 Mar 31 (Volume 88)
  - Minute books, 1994 Apr 1-1994 Dec 29 (Volume 89)
  - Minute books, 1995 Jan 3-1995 Sept 26 (Volume 90)
  - Minute books, 1995 Oct 2-1996 June 28 (Volume 91)
  - Minute books, 1996 July 1-1997 June 25 (Volume 92)
  - Minute books, 1997 July 1-1998 Mar 30 (Volume 93)
  - Minute books, 1998 Apr 1-1998 Dec 28 (Volume 94)
  - Minute books, Index A, 1934 Mar 22-1947 May 29 (Volume 1)
  - Minute books, Index A-2, 1947 June 2-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 2)
  - Minute books, Index A-3, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 3)
  - Minute books, Index B, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 4)
  - Minute books, Index B-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 5)
  - Minute books, Index C, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 6)
  - Minute books, Index C-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 7)
  - Minute books, Index D, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 8)
  - Minute books, Index D-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 9)
  - Minute books, Index E 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 10)
  - Minute books, Index E-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 11)
  - Minute books, Index F, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 12)
  - Minute books, Index F-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 13)
  - Minute books, Index G, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 14)
  - Minute books, Index G-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 15)
  - Minute books, Index H, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 16)
  - Minute books, Index H-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 17)
  - Minute books, Index I, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 18)
  - Minute books, Index I-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 19)
  - Minute books, Index J, 1934 Mar 22-1960 June 30 (Volume 20)
  - Minute books, Index J-2, 1934 Mar 22-1960 June 30 (Volume 21)
  - Minute books, Index K, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 22)
  - Minute books, Index K-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 23)
  - Minute books, Index L, 1934 Mar 22-1947 May 29 (Volume 24)
  - Minute books, Index L-2, 1947 June 2-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 25)
  - Minute books, Index L-3, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 26)
  - Minute books, Index M, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 27)
  - Minute books, Index M-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 28)
  - Minute books, Index N, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 29)
  - Minute books, Index N-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 30)
  - Minute books, Index O, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 31)
  - Minute books, Index O-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 32)
  - Minute books, Index P, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 33)
  - Minute books, Index P-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 34)
  - Minute books, Index Q, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 35)
  - Minute books, Index Q-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 36)
  - Minute books, Index R, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 37)
  - Minute books, Index R-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 38)
  - Minute books, Index S, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 39)
  - Minute books, Index S-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 40)
  - Minute books, Index T, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 41)
  - Minute books, Index T-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 42)
  - Minute books, Index U, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 43)
  - Minute books, Index U-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 44)
  - Minute books, Index V, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 45)
  - Minute books, Index V-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 46)
  - Minute books, Index W, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 47)
  - Minute books, Index W-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 48)
  - Minute books, Index X, Y, Z, 1934 Mar 22-1960 Apr 22 (Volume 49)
  - Minute books, Index X, Y, Z-2, 1960 May 10-1980 June 30 (Volume 50)
- Series II: Record books,, 1934-1985, Extent: 3.25 cu. ft. (13 volumes) (Box Volumes 1-13)
  - Record books, 1934 Mar 22-1935 June 29 (Volume 1)
  - Record books, 1935 July 10-1937 Apr 30 (Volume 2)
  - Record books, 1937 May 4-1938 Nov 30 (Volume 3)
  - Record books, 1938 Dec 1-1940 June 30 (Volume 4)
  - Record books, 1940 July 1-1942 June 30 (Volume 5)
  - Record books, 1942 July 1-1944 June 30 (Volume 6)
  - Record books, 1944 July 1-1946 June 30 (Volume 7)
  - Record books, 1946 July 1-1948 June 30 (Volume 8)
  - Record books, 1948 July 1-1950 June 30 (Volume 9)
  - Record books, 1950 July 1-1952 June 30 (Volume 10)
  - Record books, 1952 July 1-1985 June 6 (Volume 11)
  - Record books, Index 1, Volumes 1-8, 1934 Mar 22-1948 June 30 (Volume 12)
  - Record books, Index 2, Volumes 9-11, 1948 July 1-1985 June 6 (Volume 13)